

CANDRA S. FRIED

UX/UI ENGINEER & DEVELOPER

ADDRESS

E-MAIL

WEB

PHONE

ROYERSFORD, PA

CANDRACODES@GMAIL.COM

CANDRACODES.COM

214.417.0503

~ ◀ Σ

Z

UX/UI Engineer & Developer with career experience spanning over 13 years. Routine tasks include prototyping web interfaces with application architecture, writing HTML, CSS and JavaScript to create user-friendly designs and easy-to-read code. Provides graphic design aid (i.e. wireframes for conceptual design, brochures, training guides, logos, icon creation and more). Constantly learning new web languages and staying abreast of new development trends. I make things functional and pretty. Currently looking to relocate to Dallas, Texas.

EDUCATION

MASTERS INFORMATION SCIENCE Penn State Great Valley June 2014

APPLICATIONS DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATION LaSalle University May 2011

BFA ILLUSTRATION/GRAPHIC DESIGN Moore College of Art & Design May 2006

AGILE

DEVELOPMENT

USER INTERFACE (UI):

HTML/HTML5 CSS/CSS3 I FSS SASS **BOOTSTRAP** BUI MA FONT AWESOME

MATERIAL IO SEMANTIC UI IADE/PUG WORDPRESS BALSAMIQ AXURE VISIO DRAW.IO INVISION JUST IN MIND ADOBE XD

USER EXPERIENCE (UX/CX):

JAVASCRIPT/ JQUERY **TYPESCRIPT** NPM/BOWER **GRUNT** PHP/MYSQL ANGULAR.JS NODE.JS AMCHARTS.JS CHARTS.JS MORRIS.JS **EXPRESS.JS** D3.JS JSON/ AJAX **DATATABLES VISUAL STUDIO** VISUAL BASIC GIT/GITHUB **CLOUD FOUNDRY RESTFUL API**

INSOMNIA (REST CLIENT)

DESIGN/MANAGEMENT

DESIGN & MARKETING

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE PHOTOSHOP **ILLUSTRATOR** INDESIGN ACROBRAT CAPTIVATE MICROSOFT OFFICE WORD **EXCEL** POWERPOINT OUTLOOK **GOOGLE ANALYTICS** REPORTING ADVERTISING **OUARKXPRESS** INFOGRAPHICS

CASE STUDIES

NEWSLETTERS

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

KANBAN WATERFALL IIRA **ATLASSIAN** CONFLUENCE CREATIVE DIRECTION WIKI PAGE CREATION **USER STORY CREATION** WORKFLOW DIAGRAMS ARCHITECTURE DIAGRAMS **TECHNICAL WRITING** SEO SHAREPOINT

EXPERIENCE

CYBERSECURITY AUTOMATION ENGINEER

Comcast / West Chester, PA / December 2017 – Present

Lead Design Engineer for the Security Development & Analytics (SDA) Team. Our focus is centered on supporting all automation and development efforts within the Cybersecurity organization. I apply and integrate emerging technological trends to new and existing systems. I am responsible for writing high quality source code to complete applications within deadlines. My project involvement includes: idea/concept phase with stakeholders, wireframing/prototyping, UI architecture management, development using HTML/CSS/Angular (Javascript/Typescript), RESTful API calls and integration, testing, debugging and hosting applications (Github and Cloud Foundry). Additional responsibilities often include designing logos across divisions for marketing materials, creation of on-boarding training guides for all new engineers/developers, and 2019 mentee in Comcast's CLEAR (Comcast Leadership Engineering Achievements & Relationships) Mentorship program. Recent projects include: DDoS Services Platform (DSP), Matador, Insights, and Wireless Registration Portal (WRP).

SENIOR WEB DESIGNER

Comcast (via Xavient IT Consulting Agency) / West Chester, PA / June 2017 – December

Worked as a member of the ANSE Team as Design Lead of internally hosted websites and applications. Tasked with understanding all graphic and web design needs, and Front-End development (HTML, CSS, Javascript, Git/Command Line, etc). Regular use of the following software/technologies: Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Axure, Balsamiq, Invision, Just In Mind, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Github, Gitbash, Bower, NPM, Node.js, Express.js, Chart.js, Morris.js, D3 Charts, Datatables, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Font-Awesome, Jade, and more.

UIX DESIGNER & DEVELOPER

GeoDecisions / Philadelphia, PA / Aug. 2016 – May 2017

UIX Designer and Developer working from both the Philadelphia and Harrisburg offices. Supportive role for enterprise solutions development, leveraging responsive design techniques in both Agile and Waterfall environments. A player on the software development team working on client requirements. Design lead for creating user interfaces for web applications while conducting usability (A/B) testing. Development of design using Javascript and mocking frameworks (i.e. Balsamiq, Axure, Visual Studio and the Adobe Creative Suite). Geospatial UIX Consultant for Pennsylvania Department of Transportation (PENNDOT) as a representative of GeoDecisions and Gannett Fleming.

WEB CONTENT DEVELOPER

Affiliated Distributors (AD) / Wayne, PA / Sept. 2014 – Aug. 2016

- Creating, developing, and maintaining company's web presence through HTML, CSS, Javascript and the use of Content Management System (CMS) such as Drupal, Vignette.
- Tracking and reporting all site metrics with B.I. tools such as Google Analytics.
- Monitoring and adjusting content in support of SEO targets.
- Overseeing web requests and performing quality assurance testing for several projects.
- Creative direction and consultation for future online efforts in support of ecommerce customer needs
- IT support for development of new divisions, mergers and acquisitions.
- User experience/User Interface expertise, supplying story-boarding for customers and project flow.
- SEO Content Writer.
- User Guide and Site Map creator.

EXPERIENCE

WEB DESIGNER & DEVELOPER

Progressive Business Publications / Malvern, PA / Dec. 2011 - Sept. 2014

- Creative direction for designers in other divisions.
- WordPress theme creation, updates and relevant PHP coding changes where required.
- Involved in full life cycle of web projects, severing as liaison/ bridge between the Marketing and IT Department.
- Executing marketing needs from concept development to creative deliverables.
- Creative deliverables include (but are not limited to): graphic and web design, web banners, advertisements, infographics, PowerPoint presentations, flash projects, widgets, logo creation, software development, landing pages, email blasts, plugins and more.
- User training for system updates and Content Management Systems (CMS) such as WordPress.

SENIOR GRAPHIC & WEB DESIGNER

L.F. Driscoll Co., LLC / Bala Cynwyd, PA / Oct. 2006 – Dec. 2011

- Original position started as Graphic Designer and ended as Senior Graphic & Web Designer.
- Front End Web Development responsibilities.
- Worked alongside architects and project managers to coordinate logistics plans, Building Information Model (BIM), graphic and marketing items related to construction management.
- Coordinator/Designer of site logistics, and all creative materials such as brochures, letterhead, graphs, charts and trade show items.
- Worked in marketing team to create RFPs, RFQs, and proposal items.

MULTIMEDIA INSTRUCTOR

W.B. Saul High School / Philadelphia, PA / Sept. 2008 – June 2010

- Part-time instructor for the "Scholarship in Training" after-school program.
- Taught grades 9 12 multiple facets of traditional art, graphic and web design.

FREELANCE CONSULTING

www.CandraCodes.com / Remote / On-going since 2002

- Previously <u>www.CandraCook.com</u>
- Freelance designer, developer and planner for clients ranging from individual to corporate
- Commissioned for design work including portraiture, illustrations, graphics, web design & development
- Consultation for branding and identity.
- Satisfied Clientele includes: Customized Energy Solutions LTD, Singer/Songwriter Jill Scott, The Blues Babe Foundation, Forensic Scientist & Public Speaker Janeisha Hutley, Blu'Phier Publications, 518 Apparel NYC, Grammy Award-winning band Snarky Puppy, Producer Antone Amalbert, The Flaming Skillet, and more...
- To view my 2019 Consultation Booklet, visit: http://candracodes.com/samples/portfolio2019.pdf

AFFILIATIONS & AWARDS

2019 CLEAR MENTORSHIP PARTICIPANT (COMCAST)
2014 RAINMAKER AWARD FOR INNOVATION (AD)
WOMEN IN CABLE TELECOMMUNICATIONS (WICT)
COMCAST BENGINEERS (BLACK ENGINEERS)
YOUNG PROFESSIONALS NETWORK
TECH WOMEN PHILLY